Guide to the Yoshio Kishi and Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection 1860-2010 MSS.292
Fales Library and Special Collections
Yoshio Kishi and Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection
1860-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Yah-Ling, Irene
Kishi, Yoshio, 1932-2012
MSS.292
86 boxes
Yoshio Kishi was an award-winning New York City-based film and sound editor. For four decades, Kishi has been an avid collector of materials that trace the depiction of Asian Americans in U.S. intellectual and popular culture, and of materials produced by Asian American activists to counter such cultural stereotypes. This collection contains movie posters, magazines, cartoons, comic books, films, sheet music, objects, and other items collected by Kishi that depict Asians and Asian Americans throughout the 19th and 20th centuries in America.
Arrangement
The Yoshio Kishi and Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection in broken up into eleven series, which reflect Yoshio Kishi's own system of arrangement:
Missing Title
Series I: Asian Americans
Series II: History and Politics
Series III: Curricular Studies
Series IV: Hollywood Films, Television, Theater, and Actors
Series V: Literature
Series VI: Yoshio Kishi's Files
Series VII: Audio
Series VIII: Video
Series IX: Film
Series X: Collectibles
Series XI: Data Storage
The materials are arranged alphabetically in all series, with the exception of series IIB-IIF, VIB, and VIC, which are arranged chronologically.
Provenance
The Yoshio Kishi and Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection was purchased from Yoshio Kishi by NYU's Asian/Pacific/American Studies Department for NYU's Fales Library in 2003. A small amount of material was added by Kishi in 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Yoshio Kishi (1932- 2012) was an award-winning New York City-based film and sound editor whose credits include such classics as Jerry Schatzberg's "Panic in Needle Park" (1971), Alan Parker's "Fame" (1980), Martin Scorcese's "Raging Bull" (1980), and Wayne Wang's "Dim Sum" (1985). For four decades, Kishi was an avid collector of materials that trace the depiction of Asian Americans in U.S. intellectual and popular culture, and of materials produced by Asian American activists to counter such stereotypical images. His compulsion for collecting Asian Americana began in the mid-1960s when, in the midst of thinking about his identity, he began to regret not knowing more about his ethnic heritage. A second-generation Japanese American, Kishi grew up in a mainly Irish and Italian tenement neighborhood. During World War II, to avoid being labeled as enemy aliens, his father, a houseman, and his mother, a seamstress, had avoided speaking Japanese and joined a local Lutheran Church. In an effort to reclaim his ethnic heritage, Kishi, with the help of Los Angeles-based veteran actress of film, television, and commercials and friend Irene Yah Ling Sun, began to scour flea markets to purchase any materials that related to Asian Americana. Over the years, his collecting efforts preserved and amassed over 10,000 items showcasing both the demonization and activisms of Asian Americans, and to trace their depiction over two centuries of American history.
Scope and Content
The Yoshio Kishi and Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection contains books, racist kitsch, paper ephemera, movie posters, magazines, cartoons, comic books, films, sheet music, objects, etc. that depict Asians and Asian Americans throughout the 19th and 20th centuries in America. While there are materials from the late 1800s, the bulk of the collection is from the twentieth century.
Further descriptions of scope and content are available at the beginning of each series.
Separated Materials
The book portion of the Yoshi Kishi/Irene Yah-Ling Sun Collection was separated and is being catalogued into both Fales Special Collections and the main Bobst circulating collection. Duplicate materials were returned to the A/P/A Institute. Modern works of fiction and non-fiction, mainly post-1950, were folded into the circulating collections. Works pre-1950 deemed too fragile or rare were folded into special collections, along with 19th and 18th century works and oversized and Japanese-bound materials. Books can be found by searching the Bobst library catalog using the name of the collection as a search term.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and are unavailable to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Kishi's home when he moved to nursing home in October 2011. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.292.
Brochures.; Political activists.; Photographs.; Crime.; Posters.; American literature -- 20th century.; Comic books.; Mental health.; Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.); American literature |y 19th century.; Printed ephemera.; Racism.; Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Videocassettes.; Film (material by form); Collectors and collecting.; Stereotypes (Social psychology).; Audiocassettes.; Screenplays; Japanese |z United States |x History.; Auction catalogs.; Chinese Americans.; Journals (periodicals); Magazines (Periodicals); Clippings (information artifacts); Asian/Pacific Islanders; Kishi, Yoshio, 1932-2012; Yah-Ling, Irene
- Series I: Asian Americans
  Scope and Content
  This series contains serials, periodicals, event programs, brochures, newsletters, photos, flyers, posters, and books which pertain to Asian Americans.
  - Subseries A: Events and Organizations
    - Art exhibits and museums, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Asia Society events, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Asian American Arts Alliance, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Asian American Arts Centre, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Asian American Bar Association of New York, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Asian American Communications, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Asian American Film Festival, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Asian American Heritage Month events - New York, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Asian American International Film Festival, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Asian American Journalists Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Asian American Legal Defence and Education Fund, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Asian American Writers' Workshop, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Asian Arts Institute, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Asian Cinevision, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Asian Pacific American Institute of New York University, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Asian Pacific American gallery postcards, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Asian Pacific American Heritage Festival programs, 1979-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Asian Women United, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Basements Workshop (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Basement Workshop (2 of 2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Book events, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - CAVE, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - China Institute in America, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Chinatown History Project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Day of Remembrance, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Film Screenings and Films, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Health events, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Japan Society, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Japanese American National Museum, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Japanese American Organizations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Japanese Harvest Festival, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Katsumi-San, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Korean and Korean American organizations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - La MaMa E.T.C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Leadership Education for Asian Pacifics, Inc, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Museum of Chinese in the Americas (MOCA), Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - National Asian American Telecommunications Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - O-Bon Festival (dance), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Opera and Musical Performance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Pan-Asian Repertory Theatre, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Sahki, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Schools and University groups, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Second Generation (2G), Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Social Events - mixed, 1992-2007 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Taipei Theater, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Theater, dance, and performance art, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Subseries B: Serials
    - AARP magazine, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Amerasia Journal - "Taking Refuge in LA: Life in a Vietnamese Buddhist Temple" by Kishi, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Amerasia resources - material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - AMSP Picture Annual, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Asian American Repository - camera ready copy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - The Asian American Repository - dummy, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - The Asian American Repository - layout and dummy (1 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Asian American Repository - layout and dummy (2 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - The Asian American Repository - layout and dummy (3 of 3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Asian American Repository - lit submissions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Asian American Repository - note cards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Asian American Repository - notes and fragments, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Asian American Repository - quotes and fillers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Asian American Repository - source material and promotions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Business Week, 1991, 1992, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - California Magazine, July 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Civil Rights Digest, 1976, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Civilization: The Magazine of the Library of Congress, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Cue: The Weekly Entertainment Guide, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Economist - advertising supplement, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Esquire: The Magazine for Men, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Everyland: A Quarterly Magazine for Boys and Girls, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Gallery, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - George, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Good Old Days, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1863, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1892, 1969, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - House Beautiful, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Intelligence Report (1 of 2), 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Intelligence Report (2 of 2), 2007-2009 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Japanese] Magazine clippings, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Layouts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Liberty, 1934, 1936, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Life - Looks at America the Beautiful, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mademoiselle, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Munsey's Magazine, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - National Magazine, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - National Geographic (1 of 2), 1945, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - National Geographic (2 of 2), 1975, 1976, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The New Yorker, 1990, 1993, 1995, 2001, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The New Yorker - article, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - New York Magazine, 1971, 1973, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Newsweek (1 of 2), 1971, 1975, 1976, 1979, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Newsweek (2 of 2), 1991, 1992, 2005, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - People Weekly, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - PHP, 1976, 1980, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Profiles, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Ramparts, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Royal Magazine, vol. XXIV, no. 13, 1910 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - San Francisco Examiner, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - San Francisco Magazine, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Society, Transaction Social Science and Modern, vol. 10, no. 2, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Time Magazine, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1983, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Time Out New York, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - True, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - True Confessions, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - U.S. News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Westways, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Wired, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Woman's Day, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The Asian American Repository - galleys and printing material (1 of 3) [Flat Box], Undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - The Asian American Repository - galleys and printing material (2 of 3) [Flat Box], Undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - The Asian American Repository - galleys and printing material (3 of 3) [Flat Box], Undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Godzilla - Asian American Art Network Newsletter, vol.1, no.1 [Flat Box], 1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Activism
    - AASC Info, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - The Activist, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Aion, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Amerasian News Service, 1971, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - American Heritage, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Asian American Activist, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Asian Americans for Action Newsletter, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Asian Americans for Action Newsletter, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Asian Americans for Action Newsletter, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Asian Americans for Action Newsletter, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Asian Americans for Action Newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Asian American Perspective, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Asian American Perspective, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Asian American Review, 1972, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Asian American Social Work, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Asian American Women, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Asian Americans (from Church Women United), Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Asian News Service, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Asian Resources, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Asians Unite!, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Avenue (Asia), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Back-to-Back Series, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Beyond Rice: A Broadside Series, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Demonstration Guidelines for New York City", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Carribean Asians: Chines, Indian, and Japanese Experiences in Trinidad and the Dominican Republic" by Roger Sanjek, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chol Soo Lee pamphlet (Korean), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - East Wind, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Insight, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Lotus, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - New York Asian Coalition Newsletter, 1972, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Racian and Ethnic Group Population by Census Tract, The SMSA of NYC, 1970" (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - San Francisco Bay Area Committee to Free Chol Soo Lee, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Trends: Toward a New Identity: A study of the Asian-American, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Unic Expression, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - We, the Asian Americans, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Windowpanes 2003, Loyola High School (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Subseries D: Mental Health
    - Comparative Psychology Monographs, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "Culture, Youth and Suicide in the Pacific: Papers from an East-West Center Conference", 1985 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "The First National Conference on Asian-American Mental Health", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Genetic Psychology Monographs, 1952, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - P/AAMHRC Research Review, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Pacific / Asian American Mental Health Research Center (P/AAMHRC), 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Social Science Souce Documents no.4: "Orientals and their Cultural Adjustment", 1946 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Subseries E: Crime
    - A Calendar of Cases 1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - California Attorney General's 12th Annual Organized Crime, Gang, and Criminal Intelligence Training Conference: The People of Laos, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "Chinese and Vietnamese Gangs in San Francisco", 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - "Chinese Organised Crime in the Netherlands", 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Description of HM Customs and Excise and Far East Asian Crime, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Documents about suspected Japanese gang members, 1984, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Documents relating to Chinese juveniles in San Francisco attempting to steal a car, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Information on Asian Gangs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Information on Chinese Gangs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Information on Vietnamese Gangs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Kishi's notes and files on Simon Fong and Daniel Short, 1968, 1989-1987 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Photocopies of individuals from Japan, Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Police reports for crimes in San Francisco, CA, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Quarterly News: Associations of Asian Crime Investigators, 1988; 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Vietnamese Gangs and other Criminals", 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Wanted flyers, 1988; Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Washington State Gambling Commission: Asian Gambling, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Where We Stand in America: A Report on Anti-Asian Violence and Snti-Foreign Sentiments, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series II: History and Politics
  This series contains periodicals and clippings, books, U.S. congressional reports, and photocopied articles pertaining to different groups of Asian Americans.
  - Subseries A: Serials
    - American Anthropologist, vol. 55, no.3, August 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - American Heritage, April 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - The American Scholar, 1978, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Applied Anthropology, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Atlantic Monthly, vol. 149, no. 6, June 1932 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - California Historical Society Quarterly, 1955. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - California History, 1983, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - California Monthly, November 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Forum, 1923, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Minesota History, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Mississippi Valley Historical Review, March 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Pacific Historical Review (1 of 3), 1962, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Pacific Historical Review (2 of 3), August 1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Pacific Historical Review (3 of 3), 1977, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Smithsonian, 1979, 1983, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries B: US-Asia Relations
    - "The Yellow Peril in Action: A Possible Chapter in History" by Marsden Manson, January 2, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - ["Size of Battle Ships"], January 14, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Oriental Review, January 1913 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The Oriental Review, March-April 1913 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Presentation of a Samurai Sword to the Town of Fairhaven, Massachussetts, July 4, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Travel in Japan" published by the Japan Society, New York, September 1, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Japanese-American Relations: A list of works in the New York Public Library, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Transactions of the Adriatic Society of Japan, December 1929 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "The Memorial of Premier Tanaka, or a Japanese Secret Design for the Conquest of China as well as the United States and the Rest of the World", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Social Status of Japanese Women, by Waka Yamada, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Peace on the Pacific, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The China Trade and its Influences - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Smithsonian Institution War Background Studies number 7: The Japanese, January 23, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Japanese Chronological Tables from 601 to 1872 A.D." by Paul Yachita Tsuchihachi, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Contrasting factors in the Modernization of China and Japan, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science: America through Foreign Eyes, September 1954 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Japanese Etiquette: an Introduction, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Useful Japanese: Pronunciation and basic words, November 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Everyday Expressions in Japanese" by Hedeichi Ono, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "A Chronological List of Japan and China" by Aisaburo Akiyama, 2nd edition, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - How to Get Out of Vietnam, November 1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - The Far East and Southwest Pacific, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - [Japan - US: A Yen to Control? or - "Law and Order in Asia..."], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - [Japan - US: A Yen to Control? or - "Law and Order in Asia..."], 1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Current History: Japan, 1971, April 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "Psychological Dimensions of U.S. - Japanese Relations", August 1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Expose: The U.S. and Japanese Reactionaries' Plot to Resurrect the Dead Past, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Our Two Countries: Perspectives on Our Views of Each Other, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - The War Lords of Washington (secrets of Pearl Harbor): An Interview with Col. Curtis Dall by Anthony Ailder, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Understanding the Japanese - If That's Possible, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees - pamphlets on Asian refugees, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Japan", 1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Economic Relations in the Asia-Pacific Region, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "The United States in the Changing Asia of the 1990s", June 1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Trends in U.S.-Japan Economic Cooperation, November 1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Modernizing East Asia, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Foreign Policy, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - "How to Study in Japan", 1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Magazine image of Mr. Metcalf, Secretary of Commerce and Labour at the Japanese Consulate, San Francisco, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - The Pigtail War (insert), Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Withdrawal of U.S. Troops from Vietnam - protest poster, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - "Charts Concerning Chinese Communitst on the Mainland" [Flat Box], 1989 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Chinese Americans
    - Senate and House of Representatives Documents on the Chinese Exclusion, 1860, 1890, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Speeches made at the Huse of Representatives or Senate regarding Chinese Immigration, 1876, 1878, 1882, 1886 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - US Certificate of Residence - Issued to Chinese..., 1892 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - "Our Brother in Yellow" by Louis Albert Banks D.D., 1893 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Chinese Outrages on American Citizens, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "The Chinese Immigrant in Further Asia" by Frederick Wells Williams, April 1990 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - "Some Reasons for Chinese Exclusion, Meat vs. Rice, American Manhood against Asiatic Coolieism, Which Shall Survive?", 1901 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Railroad Trainmen's Journal, vol. XIX, no. 2, March 1902 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - "The Treatment of the Exempt Classes of Chinese in the U.S." by Ng Poon Chew, January 1908 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - U.S. Department of Labor documents on Chinese admission to the U.S., 1908, 1909, 1914, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Letter to Hon. Lawrence Y. Sherman, U.S. Senate, from Thomas F. Millard on Hotel LaFayette stationary, July 25, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - "Commemorating the Eleventh Anniversary of the Republic of China" pamphlet, October 10, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - The Chinese in the California Mines, 1848-1860, June 1930 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - "Foreigners in the California Gold Rush" by Seville Sylva, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Chinese Digest, vol. 2, no. 43, October 23, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Yee Wing Chuck - diary (teenager living in San Francisco Chinatown during WWII), 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - [Chinese classics in miniature - partial set of pamphlets published by Quon-Quon company], 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)